James Minks

jminks64@gmail.com 904-654-2121

SUMMARY

I have maintained organization-wide enterprise-level software applications through best practices, staffing, and team management. I have supported multiple IT projects ranging from relatively small system upgrades to large complex integration projects, covering \$1B in construction projects. I have been responsible for planning and coordinating the processes required for the provision of user applications and systems necessary for business operations. I have proven communication skills, contributing both to senior leadership and industry conferences. I have extensive experience in the design, development, and deployment of mission-critical information and software systems, proven by my experience and supporting certifications.

PROFICIENCIES

Customer Relationship ManagementManaged Service DeliveryP&L ManagementAccount ManagementTeam ManagementVendor ManagementChange ManagementBusiness StrategyStakeholder Management

SOFTWARE

Oracle Cloud at Customer (Exadata Database Machine X7-2, Compute, Storage, Network), Amazon Web Services (EC2, IAM, S3, VPC), Google Cloud Platform (Compute, Storage, Network, IAM), Oracle E-Business Suite, Oracle Hyperion Financial Close Management, Oracle Hyperion Planning, Oracle Primavera Unifier, Oracle Primavera P6, Oracle Primavera Contract Management Oracle Database (R5-R19c, ADB), NetScaler, F5 BigIP, Microsoft Office, Microsoft Project, Visio, PWA, SharePoint, Confluence, JIRA, Clarity and CA Rally.

CERTIFICATIONS

Project Management Professional (PMP)

AWS Cloud Practitioner

Oracle Cloud Infrastructure Foundation Associate
Oracle Cloud Infrastructure Architect Professional
Oracle Autonomous Database Specialist

ITIL v3 Foundation
Oracle Cloud Infrastructure Foundation Associate
Oracle Cloud Infrastructure Architect Associate

EXPERIENCE

Senior IT Consultant, Jacksonville, FL

11/2019 - 05/2020

- Provided management oversight of IT projects for clients in the marketing (AWS migration) and hospitality (NCR Counterpoint POS upgrade) industries.
- · Reported weekly project status, issues, risks, dependencies and change requests.
- Facilitated planning, strategy, and managing priorities to deliver successful results.

Florida Blue, Jacksonville, FL

06/2019 - 10/2019

Senior Information Technology Project Manager

- Oversaw client development and project management activities.
- Responsible for developing and maintaining project plans and tracking financials.
- Directed a cross functional team of 2 business analysts and 10 IT project managers.
- Managed major operations outages and communications to business partners.
- Provided customer training on IT service desk processes, Rally tool, and reporting, resulting in 50% improvement in adoption and usage.
- Documented and managed project issues, changes, risks, and dependencies.

Oracle Corporation, Jacksonville, FL Senior Technical Account Manager

02/2018 - 05/2019

- Managed the highly successful cross-functional agile team of 3 architects, 2 install coordinators and 10 field engineers with \$2.8M annual budget
- Accelerated customer adoption of Oracle solutions by leading the implementation journey and business transformation strategies. Customers included: Cognizant / Emblem Health, Wal-Mart, AT&T, Encana Oil & Gas, Ventiv Technology, Toyota North America, Great American Insurance, Fundserv, Wisconsin Department of Administration, and Michigan State University.
- Developed strategic relationships with customer stakeholders to understand the customer's business needs and develop strategic solutions.
- Advocated for customer needs in order to overcome adoption blockers and drive new feature development.

James Minks

jminks64@gmail.com 904-654-2121

- Responsible for providing customers with the guidance and support needed throughout the full life cycle of
 hardware and software installation and implementation, to ensure the successful and most effective use of Oracle's
 products. Database migrations from Oracle 11+ to 19c; upgrading host VMs (RedHat, Oracle Virtual Machines).
- Accountable for the profitability of Oracle services and increasing customers cloud commitment through portfolio management.
- Served as a liaison for escalating customer issues across multiple Oracle businesses.

Florida Blue, Jacksonville, FL Senior Project Manager

09/2017 - 01/2018

- Supervised a 15-member scrum team, with \$750K budget and facilitated agile Medicare projects.
- Participated in sprint planning, backlog grooming, daily standups, sprint reviews, customer demos, and sprint reviews.
- Managed project scope, budget, timeline, and resources and provided project status to executive leadership.

CSX Technology, Jacksonville, FL Senior Solutions Architect / Project Manager

02/2011 - 04/2017

- Successfully managed a \$3.7M portfolio, including Oracle Hyperion Financial Management and Planning, Primavera P6, Unifier, Oracle AutoVue and Oracle E-Business Suite modernization.
- Spearheaded the architecture and implementation of Oracle Hyperion Financial Management for the Accounting team and Oracle Hyperion Planning Suite for the Finance team.
- Responsible for Managed Service Delivery of an agile cross functional project team of technical resources and leveraged relationships with multiple third-party vendors (Grant Thornton, Finit, Infosys) to ensure achievement of operational objectives.
- Formed a data governance board for CSX to provide oversight on the use of Primavera applications (P6 & CM) and with guidance on Federal Railroad Administration reporting for engineering projects.
- Lead in the enhancements of Intermodal's legacy Transportation Management System (TMS) application and integration with the Oracle Financials application.
- Participated in disaster recovery planning and testing when required.
- Facilitated project team status meetings to derive project schedules and project costs; anticipated and addressed related issues and risks; coordinated inter-project dependencies; and optimized vendor resources.

Oracle Corporation, Orlando, FL Senior Manager - Oracle Global Support

09/1995 - 01/2011

- Provided first-class Oracle eBusiness Suite (eBS) support for Fortune 500 companies.
- Built and maintained sound working relationships with the business users and the global IT teams.
- Managed 20 eBS support engineers including recruiting, training and coaching employees, communicating job expectations and delivering performance reviews.
- Responsible for customer escalations by working with cross-functional teams in sales, support, engineering and
 operations team to resolve support requests to meet SLAs.
- Identified trends, performed root cause analysis and implemented preventive and corrective actions.
- Reported on KPIs to Oracle leadership and customer executive teams.

EDUCATION

Concord University, Athens, WV

Bachelor of Science in Computer Information

Bachelor of Science in Computer Information Systems (BSCIS)

PRESENTATIONS

"Primavera P6 EPPM Upgrade Experiences in an Integrated Application Landscape." Oracle Openworld Conference, San Francisco, CA.

"The Evolution of Project Controls at CSX Transportation." Oracle Application User Group's Collaborate Conference, Las Vegas, NV.

"Integrating Hyperion Planning 11.1.2.2 Applications with Oracle Data Relationship Management (DRM)" - Oracle Application User Group's Collaborate Conference, Las Vegas, NV.